<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thaddeus's Personal Site on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/</link><description>Recent content in Thaddeus's Personal Site on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>28FEB28 - Git remote track fix</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260228/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:39:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260228/</guid><description>Intro# While working on my git repo for my research project found here: https://github.com/adminprivileges/ebpH I was making changes to a local branch and pushing it up to the remote github repo without really worrying about where it was going because I assumed it was going to a remote branch. I was wrong and the changes were going directly to main. This isnt really a huge issue since the repo is only for me, but I&amp;rsquo;m typing this out so hopefully I dont make this mistake somewhere it actually matters and so I can have the steps to fix it id it does.</description></item><item><title>16JAN26 - NextJS Authentication Bypass</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260116/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260116/</guid><description>Intro# Today while messing around with one of the HackTheBox retired machines &amp;ldquo;Previous&amp;rdquo;, the method of gaining initial access is due to the &amp;ldquo;Middleware&amp;rdquo; Authentication Bypass in Next.js. This vulnerability can be exploited to bypass authorization and access sensitive pages. Details of the affected versions can be found here CVE-2025-29927.
Background# The CVE is a vulnerability in the handling of &amp;ldquo;middleware&amp;rdquo;. In its simplest terms (the only ones I understand) middleware is a function used to process a user request in some form or fashion.</description></item><item><title>28AUG25 - Dont Forget to update initramfs</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250828/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 12:47:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250828/</guid><description>01. Intro# I use ZFSBootMenu to manage my boot environments and help me roll back when I inevitably do something destructive to my system. Today I decided to change my encryption password because my current one has a key combination that confused my fingers so I almost always typed it incorrectly the first time. I changed my zfs rpool password, but I neglected to update initramfs. Im documenting the steps to properly change my password here so that i dont forget.</description></item><item><title>16JUL25 - The Credential Theft Shuffle</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250716/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250716/</guid><description>01. Intro# I was doing the Password Attacks lab in hackthebox academy and I found it pretty interesting so I figured I would redo it and step through how I did it and my thought process to help solidify concepts and because I enjoyed this one, even though it was a bit frustrating initially.
02. Gathering Initial Info# To start this engagement we know a couple things. We have a user Betty Jade that works at Nexura LLC.</description></item><item><title>06FEB25 - DLL Hijacking</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250206/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250206/</guid><description>Today I was looking at something new to learn and I came accross some material on DLL Hijacking. Previously I was only really aware of DLL search order hijacking, but I was interested to see that theres actually several varients to this idea. It may be best to first explain what a DLL is before talking about methods of manipulation. A DLL is a shared object or a snippet of code that several applications and operating system components can import for many common functions as to not have to re-invent the wheel on many things.</description></item><item><title>09JAN25 - Diffie Helman</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250109/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250109/</guid><description>Today I was looking into some stuff for SSH and I wanted to know more about the maths behind how diffie helman works and since its just always something I took for granted so today I learned. Below is a simple graphic that I made that illustrates the process of the key exchange.
So what does this mean? Well asymetric cryptography is built upon the idea of creating a shared secret independently without passing it over the public internet.</description></item><item><title>02JAN25 - NixOS</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250102/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:04:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250102/</guid><description>So I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything today so I&amp;rsquo;m going to take today to write about NixOS. I started using NixOS recently because I would like to incorporate declarative and immutable operating systems into my research. I was introduced to NixOS via one of my favorite podcasts Linux Unplugged. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t initially sold on it because it sounded like a fad, but so far its pretty cool. This is how I understand it.</description></item><item><title>01JAN25 - Hugo Site Plans</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:04:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250101/</guid><description>Hello, this is the beginning of my (somewhat) daily blog. The intention of this blog is less of an exercise in writing about my life and more of a exercise in making a habit of documentation. I plan to write daily about lessons I learned about computers that day and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be a non-computer related blog or two. When I implement tagging and search, I will make sure that things are tagged appropriately.</description></item><item><title>How to Set Up Apache Guacamole</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/how_to_setup_apache_guacamole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/how_to_setup_apache_guacamole/</guid><description>Do you ever find yourself wanting to access machines, but due to the permissions of he computer you&amp;rsquo;re currently on or network restrictions you&amp;rsquo;re unable to do so? Or maybe you have users that you would like to have access to remote machines, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to worry about what remote administration tools they have on their devices. Guacamole is cool because it allows a user to access Windows and Linux machines through a variety of different protocols such as SSH, RDP, or VNC through a web browser as all of the tools are separated from the client machine and resident on the server side meaning administration can be done on any computing device capable of web browsing to prove it, once we have this set up i will access a remote machine via my PlayStation 4.</description></item><item><title>Nebula VPN Setup</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/nebula_vpn_setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/nebula_vpn_setup/</guid><description>Most people see VPN and they think of the commercial, hide myself within another million people’s traffic, product such as Nord or PIA. But this article is simply an interesting take on the technology used to bridge the physical gap between work-spaces that many professionals both technical and not became intimately familiar with over the recent 2021 pandemic.
What is Nebula and how is it different?# In a traditional sense a VPN functions as a router that bridges different LANs over an encrypted tunnel, and the traffic passed between LANs travels much like traditional traffic would when passed between LANs, in a star-like topology where all traffic destined for a peer must first pass through a switching/routing device, but what if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case?</description></item><item><title>The Perfect Pihole</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/the_perfect_pihole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/the_perfect_pihole/</guid><description>Everyone hates advertisements and thanks to the raspberry pi and the Pi-hole project, keeping them out of your life has become easier and easier. By setting up a local Domain Name Service(DNS) server you can block the connection to add servers before they’re even initiated. Pi-hole also presents the user with a beautiful user interface and is easily configured for even the newest of IT enthusiasts (I&amp;rsquo;m serious, its like… one command.</description></item><item><title>Automating pfSense Key Export</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</guid><description>So having keys via LetsEncrypt is pretty cool given the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re free, but unlike other certs these are only good for about 90 days, and while manually moving keys over a couple times a year is not the most annoying thing in the world, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty lazy so i like to automate trivial tasks as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this with the assumption that you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up your certs using the pfSense ACME client so what we&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing is as simple as using rsync to ensure that these files are always up to date.</description></item><item><title>Cheap Temp/Humidity Sensing in HAS</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/cheap_temp_humidity_sensing_has/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/cheap_temp_humidity_sensing_has/</guid><description>If your house is like mine you have some rooms that run a little hotter than others (especially if you have servers running). Because of this the need to monitor temperature readings in rooms became a little more important, now there&amp;rsquo;s a multitude of different ways to tackle this problem but this is by far the cheapest (although more time consuming on the front end) and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any cloud services to keep it running.</description></item><item><title>Exposing Services Behind a Firewall</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/exposing_services_behind_firewall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/exposing_services_behind_firewall/</guid><description>Synopsis# Sometimes you may find yourself in a situation in which you would like to host a service but sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re stuck behind a double NAT, or even just a firewall in which you do not control all of the rules for. Here I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use Wireguard VPN to finagle around this issue and simply give your private server a public IP address. Important note: in order for this to work, you will need a publicly accessible VPS, preferably with a static IP address, i would recommend either AWS Lighsail or Linode as they are both cost-effective options with their cheapest tiers being bout $3.</description></item><item><title>ProxMox LXC Deployment</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/proxmox_lxc_automation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/proxmox_lxc_automation/</guid><description>In an attempt to automate the deployment as well as get my feet wet with a little Ansible in my homelab i created a playbook to automate the deployment of the minimal LXCs that build to deploy certain apps like pi-hole, nginx proxies, and sql databases. The documentation on certain things were pretty sparse so I will try to explain the intentions that I had, the issues that I ran into, as well as why I chose the routes that I took for my solution.</description></item><item><title>Rate Limiting with IPTables</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/rate_limiting_with_iptables/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/rate_limiting_with_iptables/</guid><description>Synopsis# When hosting public servers, whether that be Web, SSH, or whatever you want to roll out, people&amp;rsquo;s biggest concerns are either automated attacks consuming resources and denying your access or those same attacks constantly attempting to authenticate to your application through brute forcing your authentication. I&amp;rsquo;m going to write this from the perspective of someone simply trying to secure a service that they expect a limited amount of use to, in my case ssh.</description></item><item><title>Secure Web Application Gateway (SWAG) Setup</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/secure_web_application_gateway_setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/secure_web_application_gateway_setup/</guid><description>Intro# I was a pretty big user of the LinuxServer.io LetsEncrypt container since it integrated all of the things that I wanted to put in front of my applications into a simple-to-setup container with minimal configuration. Unfortunately, the team has had to transition to a different setup due to a trademark request. Due to my own laziness, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like learning how to use the new system so I ended up doing things the hard way for a couple of years, don&amp;rsquo;t do what I did.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up an NGINX Reverse Proxy</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/setting_up_nginx_reverse_proxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/setting_up_nginx_reverse_proxy/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever set up an application like Plex with a web server on a non-standard port, wanted a bit more security to go into accessing applications over networks that you may not fully trust, or even just wanted to ensure all of your requests to your web services just go to one place so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to mess with firewall rules every time you make something new then this article is for you.</description></item><item><title>Systemd Service Guide</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/systemd_service_guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/systemd_service_guide/</guid><description>When creating applications that you&amp;rsquo;d like to run over a continuous period of time, you&amp;rsquo;re eventually going to need to worry about timing, system integration, and startup/exit behavior, but while creating your own methods to do so I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about the Linux operating system, but often times its a bit more work than one would like just to get a simple application running. For this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how I created a service to run my Eva Unit-01 discord bot.</description></item><item><title>/bin/bash^M: bad interpreter</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_bash_bad_interpreter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_bash_bad_interpreter/</guid><description>Bash scripts are very sensitive to line endings which can cause some portability issues between windows and unix-like systems (depending on how the text editor encodes line breaks). If you would like to see the invisible characters that are making your life confusing simply type:
cat -v &amp;lt;FILE&amp;gt; The easiest solution to this issue is a simple sed replace line:
sed -i -e &amp;#39;s/\r$//&amp;#39; &amp;lt;FILE&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>400: Bad Request in HomeAssistant</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_400_bad_request_ha-copy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_400_bad_request_ha-copy/</guid><description>So for some reason in v2021.7.0 HomeAssistant introduced a bug that breaks a lot of systems that rely on its NGINX reverse proxy add-on to provide ssl capabilities. Thankfully the fix itself is pretty simple.
To begin, try to navigate to the site to produce the error, then in the HAS web GUI navigate to the Supervisor Logs (Settings&amp;gt;System&amp;gt;Logs)
Grab the IP that shows up in the error that reads</description></item><item><title>400: Bad Request in HomeAssistant</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_400_bad_request_ha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_400_bad_request_ha/</guid><description>So for some reason in v2021.7.0 HomeAssistant introduced a bug that breaks a lot of systems that rely on its NGINX reverse proxy add-on to provide ssl capabilities. Thankfully the fix itself is pretty simple.
To begin, try to navigate to the site to produce the error, then in the HAS web GUI navigate to the Supervisor Logs (Settings&amp;gt;System&amp;gt;Logs)
Grab the IP that shows up in the error that reads</description></item><item><title>Change Proxmox Default Port (Kinda)</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_change_proxmox_port/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_change_proxmox_port/</guid><description>The Proxmox team doesnt really have any plans on changing the default port assigned to Proxmox (8006) and their documentation just tells you to use nginx to proxy the traffic if you want to change the default port so the following script should change your port to the port of your choosing [with 443 as the default].
#!/bin/bash#Install nginxapt install nginx#Checks for your default nginx file and deletes itFILE=/etc/nginx/conf.</description></item><item><title>Change Proxmox to DHCP Client</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_change_proxmox_to_dhcp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_change_proxmox_to_dhcp/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really like like allowing servers to set their own IP addresses, i think its kinda weird and i like to handle things at the network level so I typically have all my servers as DHCP clients and I set their addresses statically on the network device they&amp;rsquo;re attached to. Unfortunately proxmox doesn&amp;rsquo;t like that so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t include DHCP in the installer, which is fine. Its easily fixed.</description></item><item><title>Clear Home Assistant Refresh Tokens</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clear_has_refresh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clear_has_refresh/</guid><description>As much as I love Home assistant there are some small papercuts that can make it annoying to deal with, this is one of them. Every time you elect to &amp;ldquo;stay signed in&amp;rdquo; and you don&amp;rsquo;t sign out before exiting the page you&amp;rsquo;ll have a nice token sitting in this long list of your previous mistakes. I found this quick fix on Reddit, but understand that this will clear ALL the tokens in your home assistant (even the session that youre currently in) so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to log back in.</description></item><item><title>Connecting ProxMox cluster over Tailscale</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_over_tailscale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_over_tailscale/</guid><description>This tutorial is assuming that you already have Tailscale installed on your Proxmox hosts, if you havent done so look at the installation for Tailscale on Debaian Bullseye.
Install# Because /etc/hosts has priority in all host lookups we are just going to edit the these files on any of the machines that we would like to connect. To do so you can simply vim /etc/hosts and your new host files will end up looking like this with host being the node you want to start the cluster on and remote being the node that will join the cluster</description></item><item><title>Copy ssh keys without ssh-copy-id</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_coppy_ssh_keys/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_coppy_ssh_keys/</guid><description>I ran into this issue today so I thought that i would put a solution that I found on here. If you ever run into a situation in which you need to copy your ssh keys to another box but you dont have the handy dandy ssh-copy-id tool, the following one liner should work. Check out this oracle web page for more info.
cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | ssh &amp;lt;USER&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; &amp;#39;cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; .</description></item><item><title>Creating a random private IPv6 Range</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_random_ipv6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_random_ipv6/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me and (and a good other portion of the internet) you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be bothered with IPv6 addressing because &amp;ldquo;IPv4 still works&amp;rdquo; but eventually its time to grow up and realize you need to start becoming more familiar with IPv6 outside of basic textbook knowledge and today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna teach you how to create a random IPv6 private range for if you need to set up VLANs, VPN tunnels, or whatever.</description></item><item><title>How to Clone a Virtual Machine in ESXI (without vCenter)</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clone_esxi_no_vcenter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clone_esxi_no_vcenter/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re running ESXI without vCenter, sometimes really niche things come up and you have situations that are kind of a pain without the appropriate management software so sometimes you gotta be a little janky.
So Primarily you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to power off the VM you want to clone.
Then you want to right click the VM and chose Edit Settings.
In the Virtual Hardware tab take not of the name and location of your Disk File.</description></item><item><title>Object type requires hosted I/O in HASOS on ESXI</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_object_type_hasos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_object_type_hasos/</guid><description>So for some reason that Home Assistant OS virtual machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t really like being on certain versions of Vmware ESXI (typically older versions as I assume they do their testing as close to the newer releases as possible). I believe the issue stems from needing to change your virtual disk to IDE instead of SCSI which causes some underlying hard drive integrity issues that they didn&amp;rsquo;t plan for. Nonetheless, the fix is pretty easy and just takes a couple of minutes on your time and a Linux terminal (or any terminal that can SSH I guess).</description></item><item><title>Proxmox Delete Cluster</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_delete_cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_delete_cluster/</guid><description>Theres no real way to delete a cluster in the gui with out doing a fresh install (that i know of) but the following set of commands should stop the cluster service, force it to local, delete the configs and restart it like new.
systemctl stop pve-clustersystemctl stop corosyncpmxcfs -lrm /etc/pve/corosync.confrm -r /etc/corosync/*killall pmxcfssystemctl start pve-cluster</description></item><item><title>Proxmox Qcow2 Import</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_qcow2_import/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_proxmox_qcow2_import/</guid><description>Introduction# For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the concept. Different hypervisors use different file formats to represent VM images and due to the fact that Proxmox uses Qemu (Quick Emulator)/KVM (Kernel-based Virtual Machine) to provide virtualization, it in turn uses Qcow2 (Qemu Copy-On-Write) as the storage file format for virtual machines data. The process to move Qcow2 files into Proxmox may not be as straight forward as it is on VMware, but its still a relatively painless process.</description></item><item><title>Pull public keys from Github url</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_pull_pulic_keys_git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_pull_pulic_keys_git/</guid><description>If you ever want a simple way to pull your public keys from Github so that you can use your safely stored ssh private keys where you need them.
curl https://github.com/[USERNAME].keys This command will put it in your authorized_keys file which will actually allow you to use them in ssh.
curl https://github.com/[USERNAME].keys | tee -a ~/.ssh/authorized_keys</description></item><item><title>Sed alternate delimiters</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_sed_alternate_delimeters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_sed_alternate_delimeters/</guid><description>Sometimes when trying to replace text using the sed command line tool you will tun into the issue in which your text has the forward slash characters which can be a bit of a headache because thats what sed uses to delimit strings. Thankfully the delimiter is pretty flexible. I like to use the pipe &amp;ldquo;|&amp;rdquo; symbol, but pretty much any other symbol will work such as the tilde &amp;ldquo;`&amp;rdquo; or the colon &amp;ldquo;:&amp;rdquo; ex:</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Omada SMTP with Gmail</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_setup_omada_gmail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_setup_omada_gmail/</guid><description>In order to get proper email notifications from the TP-link Omada SDN Controller you need to set up SMTP and have it authenticate to your email provider of choice (here we&amp;rsquo;re gong to use gmail). This tutorial is assuming that you have a google domain because you use the google SMTP servers to send your mail. Gmail allows application access to SMTP functions pretty seamlessly so this whole evolution takes like 5 mins.</description></item><item><title>SSH Auth Agent issues on FreeBSD</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ssh_agent_issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ssh_agent_issues/</guid><description>So i was trying to make a script that would automate SSL key exports from a BSD machine to another so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the pain of doing it manually every time and i ran into the issue of me not being able to ssh-copy-id my files over but i keep running into the issue of it not being able to connect to my auth agent due to a lack of keys even though i generated them with ssh-keygen, nonetheless no matter what I did i kept getting met with:</description></item><item><title>Testing Drive Read/Write Speed Via Terminal</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_testing_drive_read_write/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_testing_drive_read_write/</guid><description>Just a quick example of how to use dd to test drive read/write speed. NOTE: Dont do this a lot or you could shorten the live of your drive since youre making arbitrary writes.
Reading# sudo dd if=/dev/zero of=/tmp/test.img bs=1G count=1 oflag=dsync This command will write 1G of zeros to an arbitrary file of your choosing. Feel free to delete it when you&amp;rsquo;re done.
Your output will look a little like this.</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu LVM Improper Partitioning</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ubuntu_lvm_partitioning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ubuntu_lvm_partitioning/</guid><description>The Problem# When installing Ubuntu Server with the LVM option in the default partitioning options, it will often only use a fraction of the actual disk space you have available. Thankfully LVM is flexible enough to extend this partition without causing any huge issues to your operating system. In this writeup, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna extend a 15G volume to a 200G volume on my Ubuntu 22.04.3 LTS VM.
user@ubuntu:~$ lsblkNAME MAJ:MIN RM SIZE RO TYPE MOUNTPOINTSloop0 7:0 0 55M 1 loop /snap/core18/1880loop1 7:1 0 55.</description></item><item><title>VMware Vmmod/VMnet Install</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_vmware_vmod_install/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_vmware_vmod_install/</guid><description>After upgrading my Ubuntu Version and subsequently my kernel I tried running VMware Workstation Pro so I could access my VMs and kept running into the following error code when trying to open the application. Unfortunately, there was no way around it as rebooting, uninstalling/reinstalling, and anything else in my usual low-hanging fruit bag of tricks didn&amp;rsquo;t work so I had to really figure out what was really going on. Lets start with the actual error.</description></item><item><title>Wireguard DNS issues with Debian</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_wireguard_dns_debian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_wireguard_dns_debian/</guid><description>When utilizing debian based distros, I&amp;rsquo;ve run into this issue a lot when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use wireguard and specify DNS settings:
/usr/bin/wg-quick: line 31: resolvconf: command not found A lot of this is because of systemd has its own resolvconf so you can simply make a symlink to get wireguard running normally:
sudo ln -s /usr/bin/resolvectl /usr/local/bin/resolvconf</description></item><item><title>ZFS Remove All Snapshots</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_zfs_remove_snapshots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_zfs_remove_snapshots/</guid><description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s good to have a nice purge of your ZFS snapshots, whether you&amp;rsquo;re pressed for space or you just feel like doing spring cleaning. The following command will clear all of your ZFS snapshots on your Ubuntu system.
Warning: There is no recovery, all the cannonballs have been shot. Only do this if you know you&amp;rsquo;re in a stable state.
sudo zfs list -H -o name -t snapshot | sudo xargs -n1 zfs destroy</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/about/</guid><description>Growing up, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much access to technology and wasnt really aware of the magic possible with computers. I&amp;rsquo;m a lifelong learner and love finding out new things that computers can do. I&amp;rsquo;m extremely grateful for my ability to work in technology which allows me to turn my curiosity to a profession. I enjoy using technology to scratch my own personal itches as well as experiment with new ways to solve problems with tech.</description></item></channel></rss>