<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LetsEncrypt on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/letsencrypt/</link><description>Recent content in LetsEncrypt on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:43:38 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/letsencrypt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating pfSense Key Export</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</guid><description>So having keys via LetsEncrypt is pretty cool given the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re free, but unlike other certs these are only good for about 90 days, and while manually moving keys over a couple times a year is not the most annoying thing in the world, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty lazy so i like to automate trivial tasks as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this with the assumption that you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up your certs using the pfSense ACME client so what we&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing is as simple as using rsync to ensure that these files are always up to date.</description></item><item><title>Secure Web Application Gateway (SWAG) Setup</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/secure_web_application_gateway_setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/secure_web_application_gateway_setup/</guid><description>Intro# I was a pretty big user of the LinuxServer.io LetsEncrypt container since it integrated all of the things that I wanted to put in front of my applications into a simple-to-setup container with minimal configuration. Unfortunately, the team has had to transition to a different setup due to a trademark request. Due to my own laziness, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like learning how to use the new system so I ended up doing things the hard way for a couple of years, don&amp;rsquo;t do what I did.</description></item></channel></rss>