<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IPTables on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/iptables/</link><description>Recent content in IPTables on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:03:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/iptables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exposing Services Behind a Firewall</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/exposing_services_behind_firewall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/exposing_services_behind_firewall/</guid><description>Synopsis# Sometimes you may find yourself in a situation in which you would like to host a service but sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re stuck behind a double NAT, or even just a firewall in which you do not control all of the rules for. Here I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use Wireguard VPN to finagle around this issue and simply give your private server a public IP address. Important note: in order for this to work, you will need a publicly accessible VPS, preferably with a static IP address, i would recommend either AWS Lighsail or Linode as they are both cost-effective options with their cheapest tiers being bout $3.</description></item><item><title>Rate Limiting with IPTables</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/rate_limiting_with_iptables/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/rate_limiting_with_iptables/</guid><description>Synopsis# When hosting public servers, whether that be Web, SSH, or whatever you want to roll out, people&amp;rsquo;s biggest concerns are either automated attacks consuming resources and denying your access or those same attacks constantly attempting to authenticate to your application through brute forcing your authentication. I&amp;rsquo;m going to write this from the perspective of someone simply trying to secure a service that they expect a limited amount of use to, in my case ssh.</description></item></channel></rss>