<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pki on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/pki/</link><description>Recent content in Pki on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:06:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/pki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating pfSense Key Export</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/projects/automating_pfsense_key_export/</guid><description>So having keys via LetsEncrypt is pretty cool given the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re free, but unlike other certs these are only good for about 90 days, and while manually moving keys over a couple times a year is not the most annoying thing in the world, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty lazy so i like to automate trivial tasks as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this with the assumption that you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up your certs using the pfSense ACME client so what we&amp;rsquo;re going to be doing is as simple as using rsync to ensure that these files are always up to date.</description></item><item><title>Copy ssh keys without ssh-copy-id</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_coppy_ssh_keys/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_coppy_ssh_keys/</guid><description>I ran into this issue today so I thought that i would put a solution that I found on here. If you ever run into a situation in which you need to copy your ssh keys to another box but you dont have the handy dandy ssh-copy-id tool, the following one liner should work. Check out this oracle web page for more info.
cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | ssh &amp;lt;USER&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;IP&amp;gt; &amp;#39;cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; .</description></item><item><title>Pull public keys from Github url</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_pull_pulic_keys_git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_pull_pulic_keys_git/</guid><description>If you ever want a simple way to pull your public keys from Github so that you can use your safely stored ssh private keys where you need them.
curl https://github.com/[USERNAME].keys This command will put it in your authorized_keys file which will actually allow you to use them in ssh.
curl https://github.com/[USERNAME].keys | tee -a ~/.ssh/authorized_keys</description></item></channel></rss>