<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>09JAN25 - Diffie Helman</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/09jan25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/09jan25/</guid><description>Today I was looking into some stuff for SSH and I wanted to know more about the maths behind how diffie helman works and since its just always something I took for granted so today I learned. Below is a simple graphic that I made that illustrates the process of the key exchange.
So what does this mean? Well asymetric cryptography is built upon the idea of creating a shared secret independently without passing it over the public internet.</description></item><item><title>02JAN25 - NixOS</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/02jan25/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:04:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/02jan25/</guid><description>So I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything today so I&amp;rsquo;m going to take today to write about NixOS. I started using NixOS recently because I would like to incorporate declarative and immutable operating systems into my research. I was introduced to NixOS via one of my favorite podcasts Linux Unplugged. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t initially sold on it because it sounded like a fad, but so far its pretty cool. This is how I understand it.</description></item><item><title>01JAN25 - Hugo Site Plans</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/01jan25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:04:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/01jan25/</guid><description>Hello, this is the beginning of my (somewhat) daily blog. The intention of this blog is less of an exercise in writing about my life and more of a exercise in making a habit of documentation. I plan to write daily about lessons I learned about computers that day and I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be a non-computer related blog or two. When I implement tagging and search, I will make sure that things are tagged appropriately.</description></item><item><title>Creating a random private IPv6 Range</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_random_ipv6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_random_ipv6/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me and (and a good other portion of the internet) you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be bothered with IPv6 addressing because &amp;ldquo;IPv4 still works&amp;rdquo; but eventually its time to grow up and realize you need to start becoming more familiar with IPv6 outside of basic textbook knowledge and today I&amp;rsquo;m gonna teach you how to create a random IPv6 private range for if you need to set up VLANs, VPN tunnels, or whatever.</description></item><item><title>How to Clone a Virtual Machine in ESXI (without vCenter)</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clone_esxi_no_vcenter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_clone_esxi_no_vcenter/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re running ESXI without vCenter, sometimes really niche things come up and you have situations that are kind of a pain without the appropriate management software so sometimes you gotta be a little janky.
So Primarily you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to power off the VM you want to clone.
Then you want to right click the VM and chose Edit Settings.
In the Virtual Hardware tab take not of the name and location of your Disk File.</description></item><item><title>SSH Auth Agent issues on FreeBSD</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ssh_agent_issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_ssh_agent_issues/</guid><description>So i was trying to make a script that would automate SSL key exports from a BSD machine to another so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the pain of doing it manually every time and i ran into the issue of me not being able to ssh-copy-id my files over but i keep running into the issue of it not being able to connect to my auth agent due to a lack of keys even though i generated them with ssh-keygen, nonetheless no matter what I did i kept getting met with:</description></item><item><title>Wireguard DNS issues with Debian</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_wireguard_dns_debian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/00_legacy_wireguard_dns_debian/</guid><description>When utilizing debian based distros, I&amp;rsquo;ve run into this issue a lot when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use wireguard and specify DNS settings:
/usr/bin/wg-quick: line 31: resolvconf: command not found A lot of this is because of systemd has its own resolvconf so you can simply make a symlink to get wireguard running normally:
sudo ln -s /usr/bin/resolvectl /usr/local/bin/resolvconf</description></item></channel></rss>