<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lessons Learned on Thaddeus Koenig</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/lessons-learned/</link><description>Recent content in Lessons Learned on Thaddeus Koenig</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2025 Thaddeus Koenig</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 14:33:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thaddeuskoenig.com/tags/lessons-learned/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>28FEB28 - Git remote track fix</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260228/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 13:39:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20260228/</guid><description>Intro# While working on my git repo for my research project found here: https://github.com/adminprivileges/ebpH I was making changes to a local branch and pushing it up to the remote github repo without really worrying about where it was going because I assumed it was going to a remote branch. I was wrong and the changes were going directly to main. This isnt really a huge issue since the repo is only for me, but I&amp;rsquo;m typing this out so hopefully I dont make this mistake somewhere it actually matters and so I can have the steps to fix it id it does.</description></item><item><title>28AUG25 - Dont Forget to update initramfs</title><link>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250828/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 12:47:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://thaddeuskoenig.com/blog/20250828/</guid><description>01. Intro# I use ZFSBootMenu to manage my boot environments and help me roll back when I inevitably do something destructive to my system. Today I decided to change my encryption password because my current one has a key combination that confused my fingers so I almost always typed it incorrectly the first time. I changed my zfs rpool password, but I neglected to update initramfs. Im documenting the steps to properly change my password here so that i dont forget.</description></item></channel></rss>